Derek Nelson

1431 Leforge Rd. Apartment 202, Ypsilanti, MI 48198 (734)274-7237 ● contact@dereknelson.io ● dereknelson.io

I want to write clean, maintainable code and have a good time doing it.

Highlights of Qualification

I love programming and tackling challenging problems with no obvious solutions.

I work to improve myself by constantly reading, listening to lectures, reading source code, and learning new technologies.

I have a good sense of humor and am comfortable working with other people.

Professional Accomplishments

Lead developer of a placement test for the Headsprout product at Learning A-Z. It is used by tens of thousands of students every year to determine their starting level. This application was made in Javascript using the Phaser game library and built with WebPack and targeted web, iOS, and Android.

I have worked as a mentor for the last 3 years. My responsibilities included: recruiting, interviewing, teaching presentations, and code reviews.

I developed an new user management system for Kurzweil 3000 administrators that is used at thousands of schools around the country. It was the first project to use Angular at the company.

I worked as sole developer to write a web application (PHP, MySQL) for a pharmacy lab at Ferris that kept track of thousands of lab animals. The application replaced a \$20,000 database purchased in the 90's.

Personal Accomplishments

I actively maintain a GitHub page where I keep many of my projects. This has helped me to get important feedback and made me a better programmer.

Occassionaly I do live game programming streams on twitch.tv/derekdoescode where I make simple games live like pong and snake. These games are written in Javascript with canvas and don't use any external libraries.

Competed in many Startup Weekends with a team of 2 other developers. We have placed in the Top 3 projects three different times. In February of 2018 we got first place at Startup Weekend Grand Rapids.

Worked as part of a team of 4 to make a Tower Defense style game for Global Game Jam at University of Michigan in January of 2018. Our game got 5th place.

Work History	
Learning A-Z Software Engineer 3	May 2013 - October 2018
Supply Chain Management – England Logistics Software Engineer	2012 - 2013
Admissions Department – Ferris State University Web Developer	2010-2011
Jung Choi (Professor) – Ferris State University Industry Consultant/Teacher's Assistant	2011-2012
College of Business – Ferris State University Web Developer	2009-2010
Computer Technology Services – Ferris State University Student Support Technician	2008-2009
Animal Care Facility – Ferris State University Volunteer Web Developer	2007-2008
Education	
Ferris State University	2006-2011